Pavlos Karalis

I'm a Full-Stack Developer capable of tackling a project from multiple-perspectives, and can dependably deliver tailored, maintainable results via a crafted approach. Furthermore, with 7 years of prior experience as a DC metro area event photographer, resourcefulness, professionalism, and ingenuity have all become second nature.

Rockville, Maryland
(301) 642-5129
pavloskaralis@gmail.com
Portfolio | LinkedIn | GitHub

DEVELOPER EXPERIENCE | DEVELOPER PORTFOLIO

Software Engineering Fellow — *General Assembly*

2019 - 2020

700 Hour course on Full-Stack Development, Frameworks, and APIs.

Traveler: Full-Stack trip planner with shared user model Project

React, Redux-Thunk, Rails, PostgreSQL, Bcrypt README.md

Go-Fish: 2 to 4 player DOM game against programmed AI Project

jQuery, Vanilla JavaScript, Photoshop README.md

Appstractor: Full-stack image filter application/gallery Project
Express, Mongoose, EJS, jQuery, Unsplash API README.md

Foodie: Full-Stack list editor with shared user model
React, Express, Mongoose, Passport, Trello
README.md

Frontend

React

Redux-Thunk

Styled Components

HTML5 CSS3

Javascript ES6

Axios SCSS jQuery Bootstrap Chart.js

Backend

Node.js

Express Ruby

Rails

Java

SpringBoot

MongoDB PostgreSQL

Passport.js

Restful Routes

MySQL

Bcrypt

EJS JSX MVC

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Real Estate Photographer - Redfin

2018 - PRESENT

- Capturing residential properties for Redfin's Maryland region.
- Onboarding and mentoring new photographer employees.

Freelance Photographer — Pavlos Karalis Photography

2012 - 2019

- Captured headshots, events, and weddings for various clientele.
- Hired and managed assistant photographers and videographers.

Event Photographer — *EPNAC*

2015 - 2018

- Captured corporate/government events with prominent speakers.
- Oversaw team travel assignments in cities across the country.

Other

Github Postman

Adobe Creative Suite

EDUCATION

Corcoran College of Art and Design — BFA Photography